现在我们已经加载了 MDX,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Now
that we've got MDX loading,
我们已经准备好开始使用它了。
we are ready to actually start using it.
所以我们要做的第一件事
So the first thing we wanna do
是确保我们正在使用的数据类型是可预测的。
is to make sure that the data types
we are using are predictable.
比如我们可以尝试延长标记或者做类似的事情。
Like we could go in and try to extend
mark down or do something like that.
但老实说，这给了我们一堆噪音，我们真正想要的只是
But honestly that gives us a bunch of
noise and what we really want is just to
得到我们需要的东西，别的什么都不要，不用筑巢
get the stuff that we need and
nothing else, without any nesting or
需要知道条款是什么，前面的专栏里什么都没有。
needing to know what the terms are,
nothing's inside of a front matter column.
我只是想能够得到一个页面，得到标题和
I just wanna be able to get a page and
get the title and
身体，所有的东西，就这样完成了。
the body of it, and all that stuff and
just kind of be done.
这使得它变得美好和可预测。
That makes it nice and predictable.
我们要做的第一件事就是创建一个模式定制,
The first thing we're gonna do is we're
gonna create a schema customization,
我们要连接到模式定制。
which we're gonna do by hooking
into the schema customization.
它被称为创建模式定制 API。
It's called create schema
customization API.
这一个给了我们一些我们可以采取的行动。
And this one gives us some
actions that we can work with.
因此，我们在这里实际上需要的惟一操作是 createTypes 操作。
So the only action that we actually
need here is the createTypes action.
这意味着我们可以进入盖茨比的 GraphQL 层
And what this means is that we can just
go into the GraphQL layer of Gatsby and
告诉它有东西存在。
tell it that something exists.
这真的很方便，因为它的意思是我可以说我想要一个抽象的类型
This is really handy, because what it
means is I can say I want an abstract type
这就是我的定义，只做我想做的事。
that is of my definition,
that does only what I wanna do.
它只有我想要的数据。
It only has the data that I want in it.
所以我希望我的文档页面有一个类型叫做文档页面。
So I want my docs pages to
have a type called docs page.
在我的文档页面，我希望能够查询这些。
And in my docs page,
I wanna be able to query these.
所以我要实现节点类型，并且
So I'm going to implement the node type,
and
节点类型是 Gatsby 的，类似于核心类型。
the node type is Gatsby's, like core type.
任何存在的数据都将成为盖茨比内部的一个节点。
Any data that exists will
become a node inside of Gatsby.
通过告诉盖茨比文档页是一个节点,
By telling Gatsby that
the Docs Page is a node,
也就是说我们可以免费得到很多东西。
that means that we get
a bunch of stuff for free.
它将为我们提供对不同字段名的过滤和查询
It’s gonna give us filtering and
querying on different field names and
各种好东西。
all sorts of good stuff.
我们想要的另一件事是,
The other thing that we want is,
我们不希望它创建任何我们没有告诉它的额外字段。
we don’t want it to create any extra
fields that we don’t tell it to.
我要告诉它不要妄加推断。
I’m gonna tell it not to infer.
不要太担心这些东西
Don't worry too much
about how all this stuff
像 GraphQL 一样在引擎盖下工作是它自己的兔子洞，它可以进入非常深的地方。
works under the hood like GraphQL is its
own rabbit hole and it can go pretty deep.
基本上我们现在告诉盖茨比的是，我们希望这种类型的人存在。
Basically what we're telling Gatsby right
now is that we want this type to exist.
我们希望能够像查询其他 Gatsby 数据类型一样查询它，并且
We want to be able to query it like
every other Gatsby data type, and
我们不希望你创建任何字段，除非我们告诉你它们的存在。
we don't want you to create any
fields unless we tell you they exist.
所以我们首先需要一个 ID，几乎每个节点都需要一个 ID。
So the first one we need is an ID, pretty
much every node is gonna need an ID.
我们用它来做钥匙，我们用它来直接查找。
We use it for keys,
we use it for direct lookups.
然后我想创建一个标题，我的标题将是一个字符串。
Then I want to create a title and
my title's gonna be a string.
所以 GraphQL 中的类型是 ID 或
And so
the type in GraphQL is going to be ID or
字符串，然后叹号将其标记为必需。
string, and then the exclamation
point marks it as being required.
所以我们说需要一个 ID，一个头衔。
So we're saying that an ID is required,
a title is required.
在这种特殊情况下，所有的东西都是必需的。
In this particular case,
everything is gonna be required.
没有可选值。
There are no optional values.
我还要把路径设置成一个字符串。
I'm gonna set up the path
to be a string as well.
我想知道这个页面什么时候更新的,
And I want to know when
this page was updated,
因为医生需要知道的是，这个页面是维护的还是
because a nice thing on docs is to know,
is this page like is it maintained or
自2015年以来就没更新过吗。
is this not been updated since 2015.
所以我要把这个设置为日期类型，这是必需的。
So I'm gonna set this as date type and
it's required.
然后盖茨比给了我们一些帮手。
And then Gatsby gives us some helpers for
this.
所以我要在这里使用日期格式帮助器来表示
So I'm gonna use the date
format helper here to signify
我想要能够做的事情像格式化日期的盖茨比
the Gatsby that I wanna be able
to do things like format the date
基于相对时间或使用我选择的日期字符串。
based on relative time or
using a date string of my choosing.
最后，我们需要页面的主体，这也是一个字符串。
And then finally, we want the body of the
page and that's also gonna be a string.
因此，在创建这个，这意味着我可以去启动我的网站。
So upon creating this, what this means
is that I can go and start up my site.
我们将做纱线工作空间主题开发。
And we'll do yarn workspace
theme-dev develop.
一旦它启动并运行,
And once this gets up and running,
我可以回到我的页面，杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 然后
I can go back to my page,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: And
现在我有一个关于旧文档页面的查询。
refresh, and now I have a query for
old docs page.
如果我查看这些节点，我可以看到我们已经得到了 ID。
And if I look in to the nodes,
I can see that we've got the ID.
我们已经更新了标题和路径，我们可以看到
We've got the title,
path updated, and we can see
帮手们教我们如何安排日期，然后我们就能得到尸体了。
the helpers here on how to format a date
that showed up and we get the body.
所以如果我运行这个，它不会出错。
And so if I run this,
it doesn't error out.
现在我们还没有给出任何数据。
Now we haven't given it any data.
但是盖茨比现在知道了，这种类型的人应该存在。
But Gatsby now knows that,
that type should exist.
所以它只是给了我们一个空集。
And so it's just giving us an empty set.
这真的很强大，因为它的意义在我们的主题中，我们可以定义
This is really powerful because what it
means is in our themes, we can define
一个空的状态，比如，你这里没有医生，那就在这里创建。
an empty state like, you don't have
any docs here, go create them here.
而不是当盖茨比说没有医生发现的时候去抓错误,
Rather than having to catch an error
when Gatsby says like, no docs found,
类型未定义。
type is not defined.
所以这是一种非常好的抛光层，你可以添加到任何东西上
So this is a really nice kind of layer
of polish you can add to anything you're
这并不一定需要定制类型。
building and Gatsby, and this does not
necessarily need to be for custom types.
你可以这样做的前面的问题，你的标记下来的文件或东西。
You can do this for the front matter on
your your mark down files or something.